[Music]
it is the crisp chilly night after our
child's first Christmas parents streets
say for a small crowd gathered outside a
boutique electronics store listening to
the man on the screen deliver a
soliloquy about how bad it is going to
get interspersed with advertisements for
Snuggies cocoa and Geico as the first
flakes fall we embrace in a Walgreens
parking lot armed with only our persons
and tattered tech company hoodies and
with you pressed up against be my
ever-present companion the racing inner
monologue gives way to the calm control
of coming up on adderall and realizing
we are in a city of millions where
nobody knows us and we can just
disappear and blend into the ether like
radio waves and no one will give us a
second thought we make our way into a
coffee shop where we huddle together
around a pumpkin spice latte
now knowing how much longer this is all
going to last but in this moment not
really caring we think therefore we are
and no one is am impotent yet so let's
vanish into the cracks of sidewalks
drink from the Hudson River and eat the
remnants of a civilization where people
would continue to stare at their phones
while the hydrogen bombs detonate above
them and the sky is blacked out so they
download a flashlight app and make a
dull-witted comment about how Obama
should fix the Sun on Facebook we as
people who aren't built for this world
why should we have to play by its
arbitrary rules can I get a show of
hands of people who still think the
Industrial Revolution was a good idea
we've dug ourselves into a hole and
instead of trying to push the dirt back
in it we build dump trucks to cart it
away
excavators dig it deeper drills to get
through the bedrock and lasers to ablate
the diamond while we run ad campaigns to
push the shiny rocks on soon-to-be
Brides fingers is it okay that we've
built a society where 13% of people are
on antidepressants
maybe it's time to rethink the whole
sure the whole had your smartphone and
flush toilets in it but it also had
heroine and Twitter and drones and
nuclear missiles and we're digging more
frantically than ever and nobody is
smart enough to know it lies even a
little further down never mind if we
finally break through to the other side
or the world is so upside down that will
literally have to lose ourselves to live
in it so maybe we should just stop
digging in
but the unions will uproar and without
the whole what would society do all day
and there would always be some kid who
thinks the whole is the greatest thing
ever and sneaks down with a shovel at
night just to move a little bit more
dirt out of the way and Lissa's friends
to carry pails of it away and the dirt
is far too scattered to ever fill the
hole back up anyway so why should we
even try let's just sit and sip our
joint latte and when it's done step out
into the night and hold each other as
wallflowers with the storm rolling in as
people hustle and bustle by looking like
they are going somewhere and if anyone
bothered to notice us we'd be the freaks
for just standing there